<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title>Auerbach_Berthold_Drei_einzige_Toechter_Auf_Wache.xml</title>
        </titleStmt>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body><title>On guard</title>


<chapter>First chapter</chapter>


 " When will the carriages be ordered? " <ambient_sound>said the servant in Gala</ambient_sound>, who opened the carriage door.

 " At one o'clock, " <ambient_sound>was the answer</ambient_sound>.

Meanwhile the women, wrapped in cloaks, their flowered heads bare or covered with a light veil, walked with their atlas-shod feet over the carpet, which was laid far out across the street.

The fortress governor, General von Kronwächter, gave the first ball today, and the first ball of the season always has something freshly invigorating about it, like the first spring rain; the faces are still fresh and so are the toilets.

The front of the large, serious governorate building was brightly lit, pitch torches were burning in the street, two police officers kept the gawkers apart so that the guests could enter undisturbed through the open gate, in front of which two grenadiers stood guard, holding or presenting rifles depending on the rank of the arrivals.

Carriage after carriage rolled up; many pedestrians also appeared, almost exclusively in uniform. In the wide stairwell, the young officers handed their coats to their boys and <ambient_sound>ordered them at the appointed hour</ambient_sound>. They climbed the broad, carpeted, flower-bedecked staircase; at the top, in front of the large mirrors, the robes were scrutinised once more, and then they strode forward in a tight posture, carrying their helmets under their left arms. The double doors opened and they entered.

In the first room, where the brightly lit chambers opened up to the right and left, stood the governor, a tall, handsome man with a full head of short grey hair and a blond beard. Numerous high medals flickered on his chest; <character_sound>he greeted the guests in an extremely friendly manner</character_sound>. Each individual might believe that he was especially invited, and that he was especially or almost alone welcome; indeed, sometimes it seemed as if the old gentleman was most surprised at the happiness of welcoming this or that man, this or that woman. However, there were differences, sometimes only one hand was offered, sometimes the offered hand was taken between both hands, a meaningful look, a quick nod of the head was meaningful. The otherwise stern gentleman was always in an affable and elevated mood when he gave company, and the excessive friendliness was by no means a pretence or deception; in addition, he had the feeling of representing the highest person, and accordingly the obligation to be gracious. Also, like many older officers, he bore a great resemblance to the reigning prince, and he emphasised this resemblance by his precisely imitated beard.

Next to the governor stood his only daughter Gabriele, and she greeted him with as much decorum as dignity, which seemed all the more remarkable considering her youth.

If the ancient Greeks had known the soldier's daughter, they would have created a type for it; for there is a speciality of the soldier's daughter that is not so easy to describe. It consists not only in a firm bearing and easy agility, but also in a certain assurance of expression and behaviour, a firmness of form that has something of casual comradeship and natural affiliation, all of which seems new and peculiar to the man in civilian dress. Obviously, these peculiarities are based on the social security and certainty of moving in a limited circle organised according to rank, in a class which, like no other, is already outwardly recognisable in a structured order. In addition, Gabriele had to represent the honours of the house for the third winter since she had returned from the Fräuleinstift. Her blonde head with its blond curls, blue eyes, fine lips and carefully chiselled face rested on a beautifully shaped neck and nape; she wore no jewellery, she was dressed simply in white with a red sash, and her figure moved smoothly and delicately.

 " Madam, have I the honour of being noticed for a dance? " <character_sound>asked a young lieutenant with brown hair and shining brown eyes</character_sound>.

 " Indeed. Would you like to draw the name? Cotillon, if that's all right with you. "

<character_sound>Only a faint twinkle in the young man's eyes seemed to indicate</character_sound> how deliberately this back-and-forth speech was made. He wrote his name, simply " Hauenstein " , for that he was Premier-Lieutenant was as well known as that he was Baron von Hauenstein.

Hauenstein withdrew, a ray of joy had passed over his youthful, bright face, but this soon gave way to a thoughtful seriousness. <ambient_sound> He heard it said here and there </ambient_sound> how much it was to be regretted that this would be the last ball to be graced by the governor's graceful daughter for a long time, for she was destined to become a lady-in-waiting to the reigning princess, whose first lady-in-waiting, Countess Truben, was the sister of her deceased mother.

The dance began and the hall with its cheerfully decorated people was a beautiful sight. It was a room from the good Renaissance period with well-structured stucco work and a colourful ceiling painting with mythological content, as the governorate building was a former princely residence.

The band of musicians sat behind a lattice covered with epheu in an adjoining room; you couldn't see the musicians labouring away, <ambient_sound>you could only hear the merry dance tunes</ambient_sound>.

Hauenstein walked past the most famous beauties, who were surrounded by a swarm of suitors, without trying his luck any further. He put the dance card in his breast pocket, as he had nothing else to remember. He walked around the halls, stopping here and there in front of a painting, a statuette or some other work of art. At last he sat down in the round room and leafed through an album in front of him.

 " So idle? " <character_sound>he was asked</character_sound>. He stood up nimbly <character_sound>and greeted his major</character_sound> accordingly, <character_sound>explaining</character_sound> that he didn't really feel like dancing today.

 " Oh yes. I can guess, " <character_sound>the major</character_sound> replied.  " I read it in the paper today. It's embarrassing, cruel. Of course he was a hard-boiled revolutionary, but for all that he had a certain nobility, something distinguished. Don't you know if he still has parents or siblings? "

 " Only one sister, but as far as I know, she lives in France. "

 " Did he tell you that himself? "

 " Yes. "

 " He wanted to go to France too? "

 " He didn't tell me anything about that, and I never asked about things he didn't tell me himself. "

The major put his hand on Hauenstein's shoulder <character_sound>and said</character_sound>: " It is not good, or it is actually good, that it is out of the line to worry about the prisoners and enter into any kind of relationship with them. The officer on watch is only there to support the prison guard. We don't have to think about what material is kept in the buildings, whether ammunition or living people. And now - come with me to the smoking room, there is Sect. "

The two of them went up one floor, and there was a completely different life up there. In the billiard room, where people were busy playing, groups were sitting, some along the walls, others at round tables. There was smoking and drinking, and <character_sound>the major invited Hauenstein</character_sound> to sit with him at a table where several officers were already seated, including the colonel of his regiment. <ambient_sound> They talked about promotions, transfers, the new shooting exercises and who was in command of them, and in between also about love affairs </ambient_sound>.

<ambient_sound>An officer called out</ambient_sound>:

 " Ah, Hauenstein! You knew the Pole who's in the papers today. I remember <character_sound>that you once told me about him</character_sound> . . . "

 " The Major knew him too. "

 " But you handed him over, " <character_sound>the first man urged again</character_sound>.

 " So? " <character_sound>cried the colonel</character_sound>.  " How was it? Tell me, and in great detail. "

<character_sound>Hauenstein began</character_sound>:

 " You know that the man - he was only one and twenty years old - had taken part in the revolution in the capital and was therefore sentenced to imprisonment. He had an unusually beautiful voice, <character_sound>but at first he sang only at night</character_sound>, when he was not allowed any light. He was allowed to do so for a purpose I do not know. "

 " Yes, " <character_sound>the major interjected</character_sound>, " I received the order and I came into contact with the prisoner at that time. But please, go on. "

 " It was granted him, " <character_sound>he then continued</character_sound>, " to study military technicalities, and one day when I was on guard duty, <character_sound>I got into a conversation with him</character_sound> and found a highly educated, enthusiastic young man, but unfortunately lost in fixed ideas. Of course, I very soon gave up trying to convert him, because that was neither my job nor was I capable of it. <character_sound>He openly confessed to me</character_sound> that he wished to train himself in solitude as a military commander; for he was determined, when what he called freedom called him again, to place himself at the head of the revolutionary army. <character_sound>I begged him</character_sound> not to speak of it, <character_sound>and he kindly apologised</character_sound>. I got him some music <character_sound>after I had asked beforehand</character_sound>. He liked to read music in scores. He was not granted an instrument, for which he had petitioned many times, but music as a common neutral ground offered us many amusing relationships and debates, <character_sound>because he claimed</character_sound> that the Germans and Italians were not suited to state life because they were predominantly musical. "

 " Strange! " <character_sound>interjected the colonel</character_sound>, " but please, go on. He interests me very much. "

<character_sound>Hauenstein continued</character_sound>:

 " And so a friendly relationship gradually developed between us over the years, <character_sound>so that the young man assured me in exuberant terms</character_sound>, <character_sound>how much he thanked me</character_sound>, <character_sound>and vowed</character_sound> to visit me in the first hour when he had regained his freedom. <character_sound>I said nothing in reply</character_sound>, <character_sound>but gave the order</character_sound> that if he asked to be announced, he should be told that I was not at home. For the last six weeks, the young man had been making lines on the wall and erasing one every day; each erased line brought him closer to the time when his dungeon would open for him. I was on guard duty at the Citadel when the young Pole was to be released at eight o'clock. The police director of our town arrived early in the morning, and with him two strange men. <character_sound>He handed me an order from the ministry</character_sound> that I was to hand over the young prisoner to the two men. I didn't know what it meant, but I must say it was a bitter task. Meanwhile, I led the two men to him in the cell. When the Pole saw them, <character_sound>he cried out in a heart-piercing voice</character_sound>: "These are my executioners! And that you of all people have to hand me over to them! But you are not to blame. Forgive me." - I turned away and the two men walked behind, while two soldiers on either side led the prisoner in the centre with loaded rifles. He did not look back and . . . "

<character_sound>Hauenstein paused</character_sound> <character_sound>and breathed heavily</character_sound>; he felt that he was not behaving in the military terse manner that must not be forgotten even at a ball and in social stimulation towards his superior. <character_sound>He therefore continued</character_sound>:

 " You read the rest in today's paper. When the young man was taken across the Russian border, he tried to escape and was cut down. "

 " It's a pity about him, " <character_sound>continued the major</character_sound>, " it was, as I said, a noble nature despite . . . "

 " Herr von Hauenstein, " <ambient_sound>cried a quickly approaching ensign</ambient_sound>, " Fräulein von Kronwächter will tell you that the cotillon is about to begin. "

Hauenstein rose quickly and went down into the hall. He was still able to manage happily, as the preparations had only just been made.

 " Why haven't you danced for so long? " <character_sound>asked Gabriele</character_sound>.

 " I paused to be all the fresher now, " <character_sound>said Hauenstein with collected vigour</character_sound> and performed the cotillon with Gabriele. It was obvious that jocular and graceful tours had been precisely arranged by the two of them. <ambient_sound> Elderly ladies, who were seated in armchairs along the walls on a raised platform, spoke to each other</ambient_sound> and agreed that Hauenstein had been granted a special favour; he was of good family, but anaemic, Gabriele seemed to favour him, but it would be extremely ridiculous if he imagined that he would one day take this child home because the governor allowed him to play four-handed with her. One of the women, in whose strongly marked countenance the former beauty and the present imperiousness were unmistakable, <ambient_sound> said with a smile </ambient_sound> that invited further conversational disparagement: " It will prove very appropriate for Miss Gabriele to live at court for a time in order to learn to subordinate herself. For it is very dangerous for such a young child to carry out her own will without opposition in such a large house, and Gabriele has by nature her fair share of strength of will, which perhaps borders on obstinacy. "

<ambient_sound> No one answered her </ambient_sound> .

<character_sound> Meanwhile, neither of the young people asked anything about the future</character_sound>, they seemed blissfully happy in the present; <character_sound>but during a pause Gabriele asked</character_sound>: "It seems to me that there is an irrepressible melancholy in your face today. Can't you tell me what's bothering you? "

 " Not here, not now! But I can tell you this much, it doesn't concern me personally. "

 " Well then, put it out of your mind. "

The young man seemed to succeed.

The older gentlemen from the gambling rooms and the smoking rooms had come to see the sensuous new surprises, <ambient_sound>and all agreed </ambient_sound> that there was a collection of exquisite beauties to be seen at the ball today, but one of the most charming was and remained Gabriele.

Hauenstein was the last dancer to have the favour of leading Gabriele to the table. As if by magic, after the last dance, the tables were set up in the hall and in the adjoining rooms. Hauenstein sat next to Gabriele. <character_sound>She excused herself for a moment</character_sound>, laid her large bouquet of flowers on the chair <character_sound>and said</character_sound>: "As hostess, I must also check that everything is in order. " She left, and Hauenstein stared thoughtfully at the empty seat and the large bouquet of flowers. Gabriele came back <character_sound>and said</character_sound>:

 " You've got that melancholy face again. Can't you tell me what's bothering you? "

 " It doesn't fit in here. We're so cheerful that you wouldn't think there was anything sad in the world. And why should we banish it? Besides, I need all the energy I can get. I have to go on guard duty at the Citadel tomorrow morning at six o'clock. "

 " Is that so arduous? "

 " Not that. "

 " So something else is bothering you. Tell me: can I perhaps do something to lighten your gloomy mood? If I can help, please tell me, if not, forget it now and tell me another time. "

 " You can't help anything. I can't tell you anything. Yes, you are right. Away with all the sadness! Life is so beautiful. Let's toast to the hope that we may always find life as beautiful as it is now. "

The two toasted. -

The ball was over. While they were putting on their coats, <ambient_sound> one said to the other </ambient_sound> that it had seldom been such a beautiful evening, <ambient_sound> and when they thanked the governor and his daughter </ambient_sound> , <ambient_sound> this was emphasised in a tone of truthfulness </ambient_sound> . It caused much amusement, <character_sound>as Gabriele once replied</character_sound> that she also felt that it had rarely been as beautiful as today.

<character_sound> When Hauenstein said goodbye</character_sound>, no more words were exchanged between him and Gabriele. He just turned and put his hand on a mayflower that was stuck in his uniform. She had taken it from her bouquet and given it to him.

<ambient_sound>Comrades shouted in the street</ambient_sound>:

 " Hauenstein! Come on, we're going to the casino. Nordeck has lost three bottles of Sect in a bet. Come with us! "

<character_sound>Hauenstein apologised</character_sound>, he was tired and had to be on watch tomorrow. <ambient_sound>Some of his comrades called after him</ambient_sound>: "We're coming to your place tomorrow evening for a whist party. Make sure you have a punch bowl. "

<chapter>Chapter two</chapter>


It was a cold, wet autumn morning when Hauenstein marched up the hill with his company, for the citadel was situated on a hill in the middle of the town. The walls and casemates gave no indication of how large the plateau was or what buildings had been erected on it. A considerable number of prisoners were locked up here, only a few for duelling, for the year in which this little story took place was 1850; most of them were convicted of political offences. From here you could see the whole town with its maze of houses, the advanced fortifications and the surrounding villages.

Hauenstein relieved his comrade with his company, had the list of prisoners handed to him and stared for a long time at a name that was crossed out, but throwing his head back, <character_sound>he said to himself</character_sound>: " The major is right, we don't have to ask about the material, whether ammunition or human lives are to be guarded. "

Hauenstein was tired and, after inspecting the guard, lay down on the cot.

But he had scarcely lain down when the prison guard stood before him and <character_sound>asked for assistance</character_sound>.

 " What's the matter? Has a prisoner broken through? "

 " Oh no. I just don't know how to help myself any more <character_sound>and have promised the prisoner</character_sound> to take you to him. "

 " I have nothing to do with him. "

 " <character_sound>I said that too</character_sound>, but the man will do himself harm if we don't calm him down, and his fate is so sad. "

 " Who is it? "

 " Number five. "

Hauenstein looked, it was a former lawyer's clerk from a neighbouring village. Hauenstein went to the man in the cell.

 " Lieutenant, " <character_sound> cried a man with a grey beard and a stern face</character_sound>.  " I'll go mad or I'll die if you don't help me. "

 " What is it, what is it? "

 " I have a letter, my wife is dying. <character_sound> She keeps calling for me with the last of her strength</character_sound> . Mr Lieutenant! With the last thing I have left, with the most sacred thing, with respect for myself and for the truth <character_sound>I swear to you</character_sound>: I will be back here by ten o'clock; let me out, let me bring the last comfort to my long-suffering wife! "

 " You know what I'll face if I let you out. "

 " I know it! <character_sound>And that's why I vow to you</character_sound>, I will not be to blame for the hardest thing in the world - and the hardest thing is that you should no longer have faith in any human being in the world - I will not be to blame for it, and if I collapse. And <character_sound>that's why I implore you</character_sound> to release me for a few hours, I'll be back at the appointed minute. Lieutenant, you are my master, but you are also my son! You have a father, you have a mother. The smoke is rising - over there, you can see it. Could you also hear the cry of lamentation that a dying woman is crying out there, a loving wife! One day, when you call a loving wife your own, may you be repaid a thousandfold! When you stand at the altar, an invisible blessing will descend upon you. And think of nothing now but that you have a heart. <character_sound>I implore you</character_sound>, <character_sound> a dying woman calls with me</character_sound> . "

 " <character_sound>I will report to the Commandant immediately</character_sound>. "

 " That would be too late. Oh, Lieutenant, you feel my cruel situation, have the courage to believe in a man, your faith shall be vindicated. <character_sound> A desperate man calls</character_sound> , <character_sound> a dying man calls with him</character_sound> . Release me for a few hours! "

 " Good, so be it! Don't waste any more energy talking. Give me your hand. "

 " Here, my hand. Every word I would swear now would be a sin. My hand tells you everything, and now please, not another minute, every minute could be the last! "

The man was dismissed and Hauenstein returned to the guardroom. He did not think much more about what had happened; he was soldier enough not to ponder over a step he had taken. He had acted on the spur of the moment, the deed had been done, and there was no need for any further reflection.

The hours passed slowly. <ambient_sound>The clock struck ten o'clock</ambient_sound>.

 " Is the man at number five back yet? "

 " No. "

 " Go out and see if he doesn't come along the path. But come back at once. "

The orderly went out, but came back at once <character_sound>and reported</character_sound> that nothing was seen.

 " So go out again and look around, I'll be back soon. "

Hauenstein went out onto the drawbridge. He could see all around the land, he had his tube, but he saw nothing. - But now, now he could see something! The colonel rode up on his grey horse and behind him the orderly. The storm blew into the young man's hot face and he said to himself: now it's all over for you.

The colonel comes closer and closer, he stops on the bridge <character_sound>and asks</character_sound>:

 " Why are you here? "

 " Colonel, I've made a mistake, a serious one. "

<character_sound>With brief words, Hauenstein</character_sound> reported what he had done.

 " How did you come to make such a grave mistake? You know what it says. I cannot spare you. I already noticed yesterday that you are not without sympathy for certain criminals. Lead the way! Don't you hear me? You go ahead, I'll follow behind. "

Hauenstein led the way, head bowed, the soldiers stepped under their rifles, the colonel dismounted, Hauenstein was relieved and placed under house arrest.

Hauenstein sat in solitude, dull and heavy, and his first thought was not of his own suffering, but of Gabriele's. How it will tear her heart apart. But it must be borne! What an infinite gulf lies between today and yesterday! And how is it possible that the man <character_sound>who spoke so movingly</character_sound> can be so faithless? Oh, of course, the people who want to overthrow the power of the state, to whom no oath is sacred, who do not keep faith with the whole, how should they do so to the individual? <character_sound>And the man said</character_sound>: I will take the blame that you should no longer believe anyone. Ridiculous! He can easily carry that . . . Along with the bitterness, remorse and a sense of guilt settled on the young man's chest. <character_sound>And suddenly he cried out loudly</character_sound>: "You are a revolutionary too, you bent and broke the law because you thought you were entitled to do so. You shook the rock of order and now it is rolling down on you, crushing you. And this will now go from mouth to mouth throughout the garrison, and the best thing they will say will be: What a pity it is for Hauenstein that he is being cassared. He was a good soldier and had every right to join the general staff. But, of course, he was on the inside with the revolutionaries.

<chapter>Chapter Three</chapter>


At the same hour there was a cheerful atmosphere in the governor's house; for the morning after a successful feast is always a special pleasure, and with the numerous and well-practised servants in the living rooms there was no sign of the festivity of the previous night.

The breakfast room was cosy and testified to the daughter of the house's sense of beauty. A bright open fire was burning in the fireplace, and on the table were bouquets of yesterday's flowers in two frosted green vases of Venetian glass.

When the father had entered <character_sound>and greeted Gabriele warmly</character_sound>, <character_sound>she said</character_sound>:

 " It must make you quite happy, too, how beautiful and harmonious the evening went. I believe the people <ambient_sound>who told us</ambient_sound> that they had a happy time. But why do you look so gloomy? "

 " I mean, you should have told me that you were dancing the cotillon with Lieutenant Hauenstein. It was noticeable to me and, it seems to me, to many others. Why did you do it? "

 " Why? He's the best dancer in the garrison, and you think a lot of him. <character_sound>You have often told me</character_sound> how good a comrade his father was. "

 " Yes, that's all very well and nothing improper about it, but, as I said, it's striking. "

 " Conspicuous? "

 " Yes. You are my good and clever child and I am not a tyrant father. <character_sound>I only want to tell you</character_sound>: You are now entering the great world, and it would be painful for me if you were to become involved in something that you might later regret. I wish that no thought of yours had previously been turned to another; rather, you should devote your whole, full soul to that to which you will one day belong. So, for your own sake, I wish that before you know the world and the world knows you, you give no one any hope. By this nobody, my child - be careful - by this nobody I also mean yourself. Don't you realise that? "

<character_sound>Gabriele nodded silently</character_sound>, and the governor did not press for an answer. He knew how faithfully his child listened to every reminder.

The servant brought several letters on a board. The governor took one out <character_sound>and said</character_sound>:

 " This is from Aunt Truben, it is for you, Gabriele. "

He handed her the letter, Gabriele vomited it and read it while her father quickly looked through the letters addressed to him. He put the letters back <character_sound>and asked</character_sound>:

 " What does the aunt write? Just tell me the main thing. "

 " She writes, " <character_sound>disengaged Gabriele</character_sound>, " " the Princess has taken a great deal of pleasure in your photograph, she finds you very similar to your blessed mother. She only wishes to read one more letter from you in order to have a photograph of your inner self. But I don't have one that I can show her. So write me an ostensible letter addressed entirely to me, but containing nothing that is unnecessary for the Princess.  " "

 " What should I write? " <character_sound>asked Gabriele</character_sound>.

 " Describe yesterday's ball. Just be completely unbiased. That's always best. "

While the governor lit a cigar, <ambient_sound> the colonel was reported </ambient_sound> .

Gabriele quickly moved away. The colonel entered <character_sound>and reported what had happened</character_sound>.

 " Incomprehensible! The matter is not within his competence! " <character_sound>cried the governor</character_sound>. The colonel, too, found the matter as striking as it was sad. He soon departed again <character_sound>and the governor ordered</character_sound> his horse to be saddled.

The governor did not think long about whether he should tell Gabrielen. <character_sound>He sent for her</character_sound> <character_sound>and said</character_sound>:

 " Lieutenant von Hauenstein has violated the service regulations in the most flagrant manner. He will be court-martialled. " <character_sound>He paused</character_sound>. Gabriele did not waver, <character_sound>she asked in a firm voice</character_sound>:

 " What did he do? "

<character_sound>The governor reported briefly</character_sound> <character_sound>and added</character_sound>:

 " He is sentenced to death, but he will not be shot. "

 " So that's what he was going to do and that's why he was so sad! " <character_sound>she cried</character_sound>, " and how could he say that I couldn't help? I could stop him, he had to tell me. How could he destroy our lives like that, so wilfully, for nothing? "

The governor wanted to say: I fear my warning is already too late, but he suppressed it <character_sound>and only said</character_sound>:

 " It is good, Gabriele, that I alone hear this from you, and I hope that I, too, will not have to hear anything more of the kind from you. Calm yourself with the thought that you were saved from going astray at the right time. "

 " But, you loved him too, you appreciated him. "

 " I don't deny that, but now he's lost. What a pity! It's just lucky that his father won't live to see it. Oh, the world, the world, the youth! "

The governor rode to the citadel himself. As he rode up the hill, <character_sound>he saw a man panting</character_sound> and raising his hands to follow him. He stopped <character_sound>and the man shouted</character_sound> with a distraught face:

 " O, what luck that I should meet you! "

It was the dismissed man. <character_sound>He told me</character_sound> that Hauenstein had given him his freedom, <character_sound>that he had promised</character_sound> to come back before the Ronde arrived, but that he had not been able to keep it, for when he came home his wife lay in a deep slumber, she had not closed an eye for three days, <character_sound>but was always calling for him</character_sound>; there he sat by her bedside, hour after hour passed, he wanted to leave, to honour his word, but he could not leave. The sick woman awoke and died in his arms. <character_sound>He begged urgently</character_sound> that the lieutenant should not be remunerated for having let his heart speak for an hour under his uniform.

<character_sound>The governor only said</character_sound>:

 " It's fine. Get back to me. "

He turned back and wondered whether he should tell Gabriele that the man had given himself up voluntarily. If he told Gabriele that, it was like an agreement. Therefore it is better that she should suffer, then she will tear him completely out of her soul in her grief; Hauenstein will have to be punished after all, and he will be suspected for the rest of his life.

The governor rode home <character_sound>and asked for his daughter</character_sound>. <ambient_sound>I was told</ambient_sound> that she had left. To where? The village where the lawyer's family lived was named. The horse was still saddled, the governor rode after his daughter and met her at the prisoner's daughter's house of mourning. Gabriele came to meet him <character_sound>and called</character_sound>:

 " <character_sound>The man has kept his word</character_sound> and our friend will go free. "

The governor sat down in the car with Gabriele <character_sound>and said</character_sound>:

 " How could you, as my daughter, forget yourself so far as to go here? "

 " O, father, it is precisely because I am fortunate enough to have you as my father, precisely because we grow up and live in sheltered circumstances, that we have the duty to support and guide the lost. "

The governor looked in amazement at his child, who seemed to have matured into a freer life on this one day.

Gabriele locked herself in her room at home and wrote all day and almost all night.

* *
*

It was evening. They were having tea in the princely palace.

<character_sound>The princess said</character_sound>:

 " Dear Countess Truben, have you not yet had a letter from your niece? "

 " Indeed I have. "

She handed the letter to Gabrielens <character_sound>and the princess said</character_sound>: " It's very large. Won't you read it to me? "

<character_sound>And the countess read her niece's moving letter about the death of the young Pole and the return of the advocate's clerk</character_sound>, and without meaning to, Hauenstein stood there in all his splendour. The family and the house and that bitter moment when the prisoner tore himself away from the corpse were described in a deeply shattering way. But one passage in the letter had to be read twice. It read: "I have looked into a completely strange world. These are people of a different religion, they call it political freedom, and are prepared to suffer any martyrdom. Isn't love and tolerance also required? They have a firm belief in their religion. As I stood beside the girl whose father is in prison while her mother is dead - oh, <character_sound>I cried out</character_sound>, yes, he is pardoned by God who, sitting on the throne here, can forgive and give mercy . . . . "

A few days later, the lawyer was pardoned and emigrated with his daughter.

Hauenstein had to serve a long prison sentence in a fortress and only succeeded in regaining his full military honour and glory during the storming of the Düppel entrenchments.

The lovers' loyalty proved victorious over all obstacles and contradictions.

In the letter of the emigrant to the wedding it said:

She has done many good and beautiful things for you and me; she will be blessed to accomplish many more good and beautiful things through a long life. "
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>