<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title>Silberstein_August_The_Loewe_of_Aspern.xml</title>
        </titleStmt>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body><title>The Lion of Aspern</title>

When the heart wants to despair of God and the invisible - it flees for comfort and upliftment to a specially built place, the church. But when the heart wants to despair of the visible, of people, even of its own people - where does it turn?

In such a case, I have seen for myself holy, great and sublime places! And if I am so clever or so foolish as to feel an unnameable, an inexpressible something within me over the course of time, which seeks to resemble a cry of pain and a howl of derision at the same time, then I tear myself away from my everyday surroundings and make a pilgrimage to such a place as I have chosen for myself.

Laugh or weep at my thinking; I was recently in a similar mood - I had read about Cherbourg, Negro slavery, German-Danish, Napoleon's statues etc. etc., I had to seek out a place of my old holy kind once again!

Outside the Tabor line of Vienna, towards the Hungarian border and the Danube, stretches a region as charming and romantic as if it had been written by a German academy of scholars. You may well think that it resembles the Hasenhaide of Berlin, with the difference that it is criss-crossed by avenues. All the fresh greenery on it would surely be declared by the authors, if they still had to revise, to be printing errors.

I want to take a trip to this romantic area. Don't tell me that I'm suffocating from the heat and dust, that I'm dying from the endless avenues of poplars; that's where I'm going, I want to go to Aspern right now, to the holy place of Aspern!

No sooner said than done! Soon I was in front of Vienna. Soon I crossed the Danube bridge, twenty-four yokes wide, and several others, passed through Florisdorf and beyond, then turned right into the Marchfeld, whose plains are immeasurable, towards the holy Wahlstatt, where the unconquerable Corse was conquered for the first time.

Between Florisdorf and Kagran, in the middle of the fields, stands an earthen redoubt; reverent awe and uplifting respect have prevented the owners of the fields from destroying this fifty-year-old memorial with hoe and plough. It still stands with its trenches, breastworks, cannon ports and bullet holes as it did then - blood has cemented it. I could not refrain from entering it, and looking out into the plain, I convinced myself that I could continue to devote myself calmly to my reflections without having to suffer the slightest interruption from any more diversion on the way.

I set off briskly: Florisdorf, Kagran, Hirschstätten, Aspern! Believe me, my heart trembled, I was on these hallowed paths for the first time, on this ground of heroic battle, <ambient_sound> on which every blade of grass lisped and sprouted from a torn heart </ambient_sound> . As many cornflowers stand here, so many eyes might have broken on the same spot, and all the red hollyhocks and wild poppies are not enough to mark the wounds and red drops of blood.

 Can you see the little tower and the little church now? Put together in your mind's eye the dead who fell there, only there, and just by those walls, and the pale faces will stare far over the gables! Yes, it's literally like that! -

Only a few more steps and the road takes me between the village and the church. The latter stands at right angles between the parish churchyard and the churchyard, and together they peer down into the long village street like curious onlookers. I have now walked for a good four hours, the village opens up to me on the left, the church stands on the right and in front of it I see for the first time the lion erected there this spring by an association of brave men. I read its inscription, which reads:

 To the memory of those who died on 21 and 22 May 1809

 Austrian warriors who fell gloriously.

I settle down on the step. The day is hot, the clouds move across the sky in dense, shadowy groups, which only occasionally show clear cracks and almost lie on the plain in the distance.

Oh, look at the sun there with its subdued, fighting shimmer! Let us turn it into the half-unfolded morning sun; the clouds revive, <ambient_sound>the trees rustle mysteriously</ambient_sound> - it is Whitsun, the greenest, most luxuriant, most fragrant Whitsunday! Archduke Karl, the field marshal, entered the empire a few weeks ago, <ambient_sound>calling on the Germans to liberate themselves</ambient_sound> - <ambient_sound>they remained silent</ambient_sound> -; bloody victories and losses have made success doubtful for both sides; on 12 April, the "Lord of the Army" flies to the front. On 12 April, the "Lord of Hosts", the "Führer of Leaders" flies in from Paris; by the 20th he wants to be victorious and have all of Germany at his feet with Austria. - Landshut and Eckmühl! - On 10 May he arrives at Vienna, which falls without a coup d'état on the 12th, on the 13th he moves in, on the 17th he declares from there the world domination of the Holy See abolished, he overthrows it, and as there is no holy Roman-German Empire, there is no holy, only a Napoleonic-imperial Rome! - But Vienna is not Austria and not Germany; <ambient_sound> Archduke Charles's horse is still stamping on his native soil </ambient_sound> and, coming from Bohemia, he crosses the Danube. Napoleon has not yet reached his destination below Vienna, choosing the Danube at Ebersdorf, which is interrupted by islands and whose opposite bank is crowned by a forest, the Lobau. On the Marchfelde, the two are to face each other; no, <ambient_sound>the rushing Danube on the Marchfelde</ambient_sound> is to be the enemy's grave and the dividing line for now at least, for here the road leads to Hungary, <ambient_sound>and the siren of Napoleon's proclamations lures the whole East to its glittering, intoxicating doom</ambient_sound>!

On one side of the Marchfeld, crowning the Lobau and in an arc: Aspern, Eßlingen, Enzersdorf; straight opposite in the field: Bisamberg, Gerasdorf, Wagram. Here Karl, there Napoleon.

The sun of 21 May morning, the first holy day of Pentecost, is dawning - can you see the dark clouds parting there? Those are five columns forming from the Austrian army; <ambient_sound>simultaneously after a chime the columns move</ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound> they stretch out like lindworms, like huge serpentine bodies, silent and mighty</ambient_sound>! The black mass of clouds above my head, where I am now, by the lion and the church, will perhaps be good enough to hold out a little, for right there, on the same spot, stands Massena, Lannes; the terrible ones have the order to die, but not to give way! - The Austrians are fewer in number than the enemy, but they also bring 300 firebrands.

It is terrible how the columns advance. At the head of the second is Archduke Charles, <ambient_sound>the cannons thunder</ambient_sound>, countering the far more numerous enemy (120,000 against 75,000). Fearful death mows through the good foot soldiers of Austria; it staggers before Massena's counter-attack - the enemy's bullet seed covers it before the guns have time to load - the flank is exposed, the centre can be broken through and the army divided into two parts - the front is already turning, <ambient_sound> the cannons flaunt </ambient_sound> and rush back - <ambient_sound> Napoleon's hidden "iron men" also burst out of the meadow </ambient_sound> , the black and shiny eerie figures on horseback, <ambient_sound> with helmets, long swords and eerie rattling, resembling a legend from the Middle Ages </ambient_sound> . - A man called Karl blasts towards the most endangered spot, towards the fleeing Austrians.

"Stop!"

Everything stands as if electrified and rooted to the spot! <ambient_sound>Napoleon's rattling death bursts forth wildly for the last exterminating blow on the masses</ambient_sound> who were fleeing - he rushes forward, the Austrians stand and face him; he moderates his furious run - the Austrians stand, he is already within forty paces - the Austrians stand, and the mortal enemies measure themselves man for man - then the bold, black, iron-covered riders are seized with horror, their fingers involuntarily twitch on the reins, the horses stop. - <ambient_sound>It is a pause of horror and awe</ambient_sound>, of fury and humility, of fear of death and lust for life in such men! - The Austrians stand.

"Surrender!" <ambient_sound> French officers finally shout</ambient_sound>, "Lay down your arms!"

"Get them!" <ambient_sound> is the answer </ambient_sound> .

Not a shot is fired on this side unless a finger unexpectedly touches the lock. - <ambient_sound>On the French side it roars</ambient_sound>: "en avant!" the horses rearing up before the motionless opponent, <ambient_sound>the black riders come thundering up</ambient_sound> to within fifteen paces, eye to eye - "Fire!" <character_sound> Karl now commands</character_sound> and as if with one blow it flashes through all the ranks! The French horses reared up and rolled over with the black horsemen, whole ranks were torn to the sand, the black armoured men fell into disorder, they became a confused, fleeing, rearing and sinking tangle. The Austrian infantry into them, the bleeding remainder soon flee back into the meadow - Napoleon's heavy cavalry has been!

Do you see that little church with its low churchyard walls? <ambient_sound>In this church a hundred gun barrels roared like strange organ pipes</ambient_sound> <ambient_sound>and the cannons intoned "dies irae" in the most powerful bass</ambient_sound>. This churchyard harboured more corpses at once than perhaps any other on earth. These weak bulwarks were a fortress of world importance, <ambient_sound>here grey warriors of France wept with rage and suffering</ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound>here the wild Massena, the bold Lannes gnashed</ambient_sound> - eleven times in one day the spot was stormed, conquered and lost, lay man against man, rending the breast, a wild, confused mass, every chair, every plough, every grave cross became a bulwark, <ambient_sound>under flaming and falling debris they broke through the village into the church </ambient_sound> , from the church into the village to escape and to victory!

"Aspern must be taken!" <character_sound> shouts Karl again and again </character_sound> , who already bears a wound.

"We'll take it!" <ambient_sound>his braves reply</ambient_sound>.

He grabs a standard-bearer's panier from his hand, he is the first to storm and win! The night sees two bleeding, exhausted armies; so precious is the ground that even the village must be divided and possessions found on both sides. The outposts stand close together - the night covers them both and starry tears flicker in their dark eyes.

On the Danube, the fires and stormers, the doom-laden ferries, the burning and felled trees run up to Napoleon's bridges, drawing bright destruction on the water. He has already given every little island a name, "Napoleon", "Lannes", "St Hilaire", etc.; they are just damp hills for the dying to breathe out!

Charles's army holds him like a lion's claw, he cannot move from the shore and can only hide in the forest, at the water's edge. - Furious, he bursts forth anew at dawn, like a shot game that wants to gain a clearing - in vain! Six times Aspern, Eßlingen, are stormed and lost, also on Whitsun Monday, Lannes is shot to pieces and dies on the Lobau, <ambient_sound>the bridges begin to break</ambient_sound> - <ambient_sound>the French drums whirl</ambient_sound> - en arrière - Back! - Napoleon learns for the first time in fifteen years what it means to be defeated, and the world has heard it: he too can fall!

The whole of Germany shudders with a feeling of delight, the gagged can only press their nails into their shackles in fury and joy, but they must not cry and shout.

The pale, rigid Corsican head sinks to the heaving breast - the angel of St Helena rushes over it - the Emperor, who came here on proud steeds and carrosses, <ambient_sound> acclaimed by hundreds of thousands </ambient_sound>, he sails lonely, led by two poor peasants, on a small, swaying boat to the other shore, whence he came.

The floating dead in the waves grin up at the boat.

That is the great, mighty lesson - that is the stone, resting lion off Aspern!

3000 French cuirasses and 17,000 rifles were picked up - 7000 enemies were buried, 5000 remained wounded on the field, in Vienna they still had 20,000 - four generals were dead (including Lannes), eight wounded, two captured. - Also 4000 Austrians were dead, 16,000 wounded.

This is what the resting stone lion near Aspern in front of the church means.

They erected it here this year with little, but felt celebration (it is made of sandstone by the sculptor Fernkorn), but next May it will be fifty years - a green, green Whitsun!

Is it worth the effort that I - during this time - have made the long, boring pilgrimage to the holy place?

I am not here to examine the strategic and diplomatic consequences - on 13 July Charles was no longer with the army - which spoiled his life and his victories, now stand before the German God above with him and will be judged.

And now we let the clouds move in lightning disorder and the sun part mistily, we no longer need them for our campaign plan; I rise and now examine the lion more closely.

Why have they not reared it up with mighty, rending paws and a mane that one might tremble to believe from its mighty roar? - Give support to our imagination so that we believe its howl reaches across the Rhine and those who hear it tremble in the midst of their meal!

But be careful, as Germans we are modest people and as Austrians "cosy" - we feel the wounds and hear the blood dripping from the open hearts. The lion lies just in front of the church on the ground which the thousands of corpses covered and which now overshadows it, peacefully, without strife, the bone arm entwined in the bone arm, letting the divorced rest together. Our lion has his eyes closed and his mouth, exhausted - sleeping or dying? - half open. He rests his head on a helmet bearing the letter N, his broad chest rests on a French standard and several broken eagles of Gaul lie beneath his mighty paws. A spearhead, which wounded him in battle, protrudes from his forearm.

Come, ye city-dwellers - ye Viennese; - what "Mödling" and "Brühl" and "Hohe Warte" and "Baden" and "Heiligenstadt" with their "romantic" regions - come here in the burning heat of the sun and glowing dust and get well! This breath is more refreshing than your air and pumping fountains - there flows the healing spring for all kinds of anxiety, leprosy, weakness, heart problems and all kinds of faintness. This is a place of healing and no Frenchman should have a gambling den there!
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>