<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
     <teiHeader>
         <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
             <title>Storm_Theodor_Der_Schreimmeliter.txt</title>
         </titleStmt>
         </fileDesc>
     </teiHeader>
     <text>
         <body><title>The Mouldy Rider</title>


  <scene counter="92">After the New Year, worry had once again entered the house; a marching fever had seized the dyke count; he, too, was close to the edge of the pit, and when he had recovered under Mrs Elke's care and concern, he hardly seemed the same man. The weariness of his body was also on his mind, and Elke saw with concern how he was always easily satisfied. Nevertheless, towards the end of March, he felt impelled to mount his grey horse and ride along his dyke again for the first time; it was an afternoon, and the sun, which had shone before, was long since behind a cloudy fragrance.  There had been floods a few times during the winter, but it had been of no consequence; only over on the other shore a flock of sheep had been drowned on a hill and a piece of the foreshore had been torn away; here on this side and on the new dyke there had been no damage worth mentioning. But the previous night a stronger storm had raged; now the dyke count had to go out himself and inspect everything with his own eyes.  </scene>


  <scene counter="93"> He had already ridden around on the new dyke from the south-east corner, and everything was in good condition; but when he came to the northern corner, where the new dyke met the old, the former was undamaged, but where the Priehl had formerly reached the old and flowed along it, he saw the turf destroyed and torn away over a great breadth, and in the body of the dyke a hollow churned up by the flood, through which, moreover, a tangle of mouse passages was exposed. Hauke dismounted from his horse and inspected the damage nearby: the mice mischief seemed to continue invisibly.  He was very frightened; all this should have been taken care of when the new dyke was built; since it had been overlooked then, it had to be done now! - The cattle were not yet on the pastures, the grass was unusually left behind wherever he looked, it looked empty and barren to him. He mounted his horse again and rode back and forth along the shore: it was low tide, and he could see how the river had carved out a new bed in the silt from the outside and had now hit the old dyke from the north-west; the new one, however, had been able to resist the impact with its gentler profile.  A heap of new plag' and work arose before the soul of the dyke count: not only did the old dyke have to be strengthened here, but its profile also had to be brought closer to that of the new one; above all, however, the dangerous reappearance of the Priehl had to be diverted by new dams or lahnungen. Once again he rode along the new dyke to the extreme north-west corner, then backwards again, his eyes constantly fixed on the newly carved bed of the Priehl, which stood out clearly enough in the exposed silty ground to his side. The grey horse pushed forward <ambient_sound> and snorted</ambient_sound> <ambient_sound> and beat with his front hooves</ambient_sound>; but the rider pushed him back, he wanted to ride slowly, he also wanted to tame the inner restlessness that was rising ever more wildly within him.  If a storm tide came again - one like that of 1655, when goods and people were swallowed up without number - if it came again, as it had come several times before! - A hot shiver ran through the rider - the old dyke, it would not withstand the impact that would come against it! What then, what would happen? - There would be only one thing, only one means, to perhaps save the old Koog and the goods and lives in it.<character_sound> Hauke felt his heart stand still</character_sound>, his otherwise so firm head dizzy; <character_sound> he did not say it</character_sound>, but it spoke strongly enough in him: Your Koog, the Hauken-Haienkoog would have to be abandoned and the new dyke pierced!  In his mind's eye he could already see the floods crashing in and covering the grass and clover with their salty, foaming spray. A spur thrust into the points of the grey horse, <ambient_sound>and with a cry</ambient_sound> he flew along the dyke and then down the act towards the dyke count's shipyard.  </scene>


  <scene counter="94">He came home, his head full of inner terror and disorganised plans. He threw himself into his arm-chair, and when Elke entered the room with his daughter, he got up again and lifted the child to him and kissed her; then he chased the yellow puppy away with a few light strokes.  " I must go up to the jug again! " <character_sound> he said</character_sound>, and took his cap from the door-hook where he had just hung it.  His wife looked at him anxiously:  " What are you doing there? It's getting dark already, Hauke! " " Tales from the dyke! " <character_sound> he muttered to himself</character_sound>, " I'm meeting the plenipotentiaries there. " She went after him and squeezed his hand, for he was already out of the door with these words. Hauke Haien, who had usually kept everything to himself, was now anxious to have a word from those whom he had otherwise scarcely considered worthy of his attention.  </scene>


  <scene counter="95"> In the guest room he met Ole Peters at the card table with two of the plenipotentiaries and a resident of Koog.  " You've come from outside, Deichgraf? " <character_sound> said the former</character_sound>, picking up the half-dealt cards and throwing them down again.    " Yes, Ole, " <character_sound> replied Hauke</character_sound>; " I was there; it looks bad. " " Nasty? - Well, it'll probably cost a few hundred sods and an embroidery; I was there in the afternoon too. " " It won't be that cheap, Ole, " <character_sound> replied the dyke count</character_sound>, " the Priehl is back, and even if it doesn't hit the old dyke from the north now, it does from the north-west! " " You should have left him where you found him! " <character_sound> said Ole dryly</character_sound>.    "That means," <character_sound> replied Hauke</character_sound>, "the new Koog is none of your business; and that's why it shouldn't exist. That's your own fault! But if we have to lay lahns to protect the old dyke, the green clover behind the new one will bring in too much! " " What do you say, Dike Count? " <ambient_sound> shouted the plenipotentiaries</ambient_sound>; " Lahnungen? How many of them? You love to take everything by the scruff of the neck! " The cards lay untouched on the table.   " I want to tell you, dyke count, " <character_sound> said Ole Peters</character_sound> and raised both arms, " Your new Koog is a devouring work, what you have donated to us! Everything is still labouring under the heavy costs of your wide dykes; now it's eating away at the old dyke too, and we're supposed to neglect it! - Fortunately, it's not so bad; it held this time and will continue to do so! Just get back on your grey horse tomorrow and take another look! " Hauke had come here from the peace of his home; behind the still moderate words he had just heard lay - he could not fail to recognise it - a tenacious resistance, he felt as if he still lacked the old strength against it.   " I will do as you advise, Ole, " <character_sound> he said</character_sound>; " only I fear I will find it as I have seen it today. " </scene>


  <scene counter="96">- A restless night followed that day; Hauke tossed sleeplessly in his pillows.  " What is wrong with you? " <character_sound> asked Elke</character_sound>, who was kept awake by her husband's worry; " if something is bothering you, say it about yourself; we've always kept it that way! " " There's nothing wrong, Elke! " <character_sound> he replied</character_sound>, " there's something to repair on the dyke, on the locks; you know that I have to deal with that every night. " He said nothing more; he wanted to reserve his freedom of action; unconsciously, his wife's clear insight and strong spirit were an obstacle to him in his momentary weakness, which he involuntarily avoided.  </scene>


  <scene counter="97">- - The following morning, when he came out on the dyke again, the world was a different one from what he had found it the day before; though the tide was hollowly low again, the day was still rising, and a bright spring sun let its rays fall almost vertically on the immeasurable mudflats; <ambient_sound> the white gulls hovered quietly now and then</ambient_sound>, and invisible above them, <ambient_sound> high under the azure sky, the larks sang their eternal melody</ambient_sound>. Hauke, who did not know how nature can deceive us with its charms, stood on the north-west corner of the dyke and looked for the new bed of the Priehl, which had frightened him so much yesterday; but in the sunlight shooting down from the zenith he did not even find it at first; it was only when he shaded his eyes with his hand against the blinding rays that he could not fail to recognise it; but still, the shadows of yesterday's twilight must have deceived him; it was now only faintly visible; the exposed mice must have caused the damage to the dyke more than the flood. Of course, changes had to be made here; but by careful digging, <character_sound>and as Ole Peters had said</character_sound>, by fresh sods and a few rows of straw embroidery, the damage could be healed.    " It wasn't that bad, " <character_sound> he said to himself</character_sound> with relief, " You were your own fool yesterday! " - <character_sound> He summoned the plenipotentiaries</character_sound>, <ambient_sound> and the work was approved without objection</ambient_sound>, which had never happened before.  </scene>


  <scene counter="98"> The dyke count felt a strengthening calm spread through his still weakened body; and after a few weeks everything was neatly completed.  The year went on, but the further it went and the more undisturbed the newly laid turf greened through the thatch, the more uneasily Hauke walked or rode past this spot, he turned his eyes away, he rode hard on the inner side of the dyke; a few times, when he should have passed there, he had his already saddled horse led back into the stable; then again, when he had nothing to do there, he wandered suddenly and on foot, only to get away from his yard quickly and unseen; sometimes he had turned back, he could not bear to look at the uncanny spot again; and finally, he could have torn it all up again with his hands; for this part of the dyke lay before his eyes like a remorse that had taken shape outside him. And yet his hand could no longer touch it, and he could tell no one, not even his wife. So September had come; <ambient_sound> at night a moderate storm had raged</ambient_sound> and had finally turned to the north-west. On the cloudy morning after that, at low tide, Hauke rode out on the dyke, and it went through him as he let his eyes wander over the mudflats; there, coming up from the northwest, he suddenly saw again, and more sharply and more deeply, the ghostly new bed of the Priehl; no matter how hard he strained his eyes, it would not recede.  </scene>


  <scene counter="99">When he came home, Elke took his hand: "What's wrong, Hauke? " <character_sound> she said</character_sound> as she looked into his gloomy face; " Isn't it a new disaster? We are so happy now; I feel that you are at peace with them all! " Faced with these words, he was unable to express his confused fear in words.    " No, Elke, " <character_sound> he said</character_sound>, " no one is hostile to me; it is only a responsible office to protect the community from our Lord God's sea. " He set off to avoid further questions from his beloved wife. He went into the stable and the barn as if he had to revise everything; but he saw nothing around him; he was only anxious to put his remorse to rest, to convince himself that it was a morbidly exaggerated fear. " </scene>


  <scene counter="100">- " The year I am telling you about, " <character_sound> said my guest friend</character_sound>, the schoolmaster, after a while, " was the year 1756, which will never be forgotten in these parts; in Hauke Haien's house it brought a death. At the end of September, Trien' Jans, almost ninety years old, was dying in the chamber that had been set aside for her in the barn. She had been raised up in the pillows according to her wishes, and her eyes were looking through the small leaded panes into the distance; there must have been a thinner layer of air in the sky above a denser one, for it was high in the sky, and the reflection at that moment lifted the sea like a shimmering silver streak over the edge of the dyke, so that it shone dazzlingly into the chamber; the southern tip of Jeverssand was also visible.  At the foot of the bed crouched little Wienke, holding tightly with one hand to that of her father, who stood beside her. Death was digging its Hippocratic face into the dying woman's countenance, <character_sound>and the child stared breathlessly at the uncanny, incomprehensible transformation of the unattractive but familiar face</character_sound>.  " What is she doing? What is that, father? " <character_sound> she whispered fearfully</character_sound> and dug her fingernails into her father's hand.    " She's dying! " <character_sound> said the dyke count</character_sound>.    " Die! " <character_sound> repeated the child</character_sound> and seemed to lapse into confused thinking.  But the old woman moved her lips once more: " Jins! Jins! " <character_sound> and shrieking, like a cry of distress, it burst forth</character_sound>, and her bony arms stretched out against the shimmering sea outside: " Hölp mi! Hölp mi! You're such a bad guard .... God bless the others! " Her arms sank, <ambient_sound> a soft crashing of the bed became audible</ambient_sound>; she had ceased to live.  <character_sound> The child gave a deep sigh</character_sound> and turned her pale eyes up to her father: "Is she still dying? " <character_sound> he asked</character_sound>.    " She has done it! " <character_sound> said the dyke count</character_sound> and took the child in his arms: " She is now far away from us, with the good Lord. " " With the good Lord! " <character_sound> repeated the child</character_sound> <character_sound> and was silent for a while</character_sound>, as if he had to ponder the words.  " Is that good, by God? " " Yes, that's the best. " - In Hauke's heart, however, the dying woman's last speech sounded heavy.  " God bless the others! " it spoke softly within him.  " What did the old witch want? Are the dying prophets? - " </scene>


  <scene counter="101">- - Soon after Trien' Jans was buried up by the church, <ambient_sound> people began to talk louder and louder about all kinds of mischief and strange things</ambient_sound> that were supposed to have frightened the people of North Friesland; and it was certain that on Sunday Lätare the golden cock had been thrown down from the top of the tower by a whirlwind; that was also true; in midsummer a great mass of snow fell from the sky, like snow, so that one could not open one's eyes to it, and afterwards it lay almost as high as a hand on the fields, and no one had ever seen anything like it; but when, after the end of September, the great servant with corn and the maid Ann' Grethe with butter had driven to market in the town, they climbed from their cart on their return with faces pale with terror.  "What is it? What have you got? " <ambient_sound> cried the other maidens</ambient_sound>, who had run out <ambient_sound> when they heard the cart rolling</ambient_sound>. <character_sound> Ann's Grethe, in her travelling suit, stepped into the spacious kitchen</character_sound> breathlessly.  " Well, so tell us! " <ambient_sound> cried the harlots again</ambient_sound>, " where is the misfortune? " " Oh, may our dear Jesus protect us! " <character_sound> cried Ann' Grethe</character_sound>.  "You know, from over there, over the water, the old Mariken from the Ziegelhof, we always stand together with our butter at the apothecary's corner, <character_sound> she told me</character_sound>, <character_sound> and Iven Johns also said</character_sound>, " that's bad luck! " <character_sound> he said</character_sound>; " a calamity over all North Friesland; believe me, Ann' Greth! And " - <character_sound> she muffled her voice</character_sound> - " it's not right with the dyke count's grey horse in the end either! " " Shh! Shh! " said the other harlots.  - " Yes, yes; what do I care! But over there, on the other side, it's even worse than here! Not only flies and shit, but also blood has fallen like rain from the sky; and since the pastor cleaned his washbasin the following Sunday morning, there were five dead heads, as big as peas, in it, and everyone came to see that; in the month of August, horrible red-headed caterpillar worms travelled over the land and ate away grain and flour and bread and whatever they found, and no fire could destroy them! " <character_sound> The narrator suddenly fell silent</character_sound>; none of the maids had noticed that the housewife had entered the kitchen.  " What are you talking about? " <character_sound> she said</character_sound>.  " Don't let the landlord hear that! " And as they all wanted to tell now: " It is not necessary; I have heard enough of it; go to your work, that will bring you better blessings! " Then she took Ann' Greth into the parlour with her and gave her an account of her market business.  </scene>


  <scene counter="102">So in the house of the dyke count, the superstitious gossip had no hold on the lordship; but in the other houses, and the longer the evenings grew, the easier it penetrated more and more. Like a heavy air it lay upon all; and secretly it was said that a calamity, a heavy one, was coming over North Friesland.  It was before All Saints' Day, in October. During the day there had been a strong storm from the south-west; in the evening there was half a moon in the sky, dark brown clouds chased overhead, and shadows and dull light flew across the earth; the storm was growing. In the dike-count's room the empty dinner-table was still standing; the servants had been sent into the stable to look after the cattle; the maids had to look about the house and on the floors to see whether the doors and hatches were well shut, lest the storm should get in and do mischief. Inside, Hauke stood beside his wife at the window; he had just gulped down his supper; he had been out on the dyke. He had trotted out on foot, early in the afternoon; he had had pointed stakes and sacks of clay or earth gathered here and there where the dyke seemed to betray a weakness; he had employed people everywhere to drive in the piles and use the sacks to dam them up as soon as the flood began to damage the dyke; he had placed most of the people at the corner to the north-west where the old and new dykes met; they were only allowed to leave their designated places in an emergency.  </scene>


  <scene counter="103"> He had left that behind; then, barely a quarter of an hour ago, wet and dishevelled, he had arrived at his house, and now, his ear to the gusts of wind <ambient_sound>which rattled the lead-framed windows</ambient_sound>, he gazed out into the desolate night as if without a thought; <ambient_sound> the wall clock behind its pane of glass was just striking eight</ambient_sound>. The child standing next to her mother flinched and buried her head in her clothes.   " Claus! " <character_sound> she cried</character_sound>; " where is my Claus? " She could well ask thus; for the gull, as in the previous year, had not set out on her winter journey. The father ignored the question, but the mother took the child in her arms.  " Your Claus is in the barn, " <character_sound> she said</character_sound>; " he is sitting there warm. " " Why? " <character_sound> said Wienke</character_sound>, " is that good? " - " Yes, that's good. " The landlord was still standing at the window: " It's no longer possible, Elke! " <character_sound> he said</character_sound>; " call one of the prostitutes; the storm is smashing the windows; the hatches must be scraped! " At the housewife's word the maid had run out; one could see from the room how her skirts flew; but when she had unfastened the clasps, the storm tore the shop from her hand and threw it against the windows, so that a few panes flew into the parlour in splinters and one of the lights went out smoking. Hauke had to go out himself to help, and it was only with great difficulty that the hatches were opened in front of the windows. As they tore open the door on re-entering the house, a gust of wind came in behind them, <ambient_sound> so that the glass and silver in the cupboard rattled</ambient_sound>; <ambient_sound> up in the house above their heads, the beams shook and cracked</ambient_sound> as if the storm wanted to tear the roof off the walls. But Hauke did not come back into the room; Elke heard him striding through the barn towards the stable.  " The grey horse! The grey horse, John! Quickly! " <character_sound> So she heard him call</character_sound>; then he came back into the room, his hair dishevelled but his grey eyes shining.   " The wind has changed! " <character_sound> he cried</character_sound> -, " to the north-west, halfway across the spring tide! No wind; - we have never experienced such a storm! " Elke had turned deathly pale: " And you have to go out again? " He took both her hands and pressed them into his as if in convulsions: " I must, Elke. " She slowly raised her dark eyes to his, and they looked at each other for a few seconds, but it seemed like an eternity.  " Yes, Hauke, " <character_sound> said the woman</character_sound>; " I know it well, you must! " <ambient_sound> Then it trotted outside the door of the house</ambient_sound>. She threw her arms round his neck, and for a moment it seemed as if she could not let him go; but even that was only a moment.  " This is our fight! " <character_sound> said Hauke</character_sound>; " you are safe here; no flood has yet risen to this house. And pray to God that he may be with me too! " Hauke wrapped himself in his coat, and Elke took a scarf and wrapped it carefully around his neck; she wanted to speak a word, but her trembling lips prevented her from doing so.  <ambient_sound> Outside, the grey horse neighed</ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound> so that it sounded like a trumpet in the howling of the storm</ambient_sound>. Elke had gone out with her husband; <ambient_sound> the old ash tree creaked</ambient_sound> as if it was about to fall apart.  "Get on, master!" <character_sound> cried the servant</character_sound>, "the grey horse is like mad; the reins could snap. " Hauke threw his arms around his wife: " I'll be back at sunrise! " </scene>


  <scene counter="104">He had already jumped on his horse; the beast rose up with its front hooves; then, like a war-stallion rushing into battle, <ambient_sound>it chased down the dockyard with its rider, out into the night and the howling of the storm</ambient_sound>.  " Father, my father! " <character_sound> cried a pitiful child's voice behind him</character_sound>: " My dear father! " Wienke had run after him in the dark; but after only a hundred paces she stumbled over a heap of earth and fell to the ground.  <character_sound> The servant Iven Johns brought the crying child back to her mother</character_sound>; she leaned against the trunk of the ash tree, <ambient_sound> whose branches whipped the air above her</ambient_sound>, and stared absently out into the night in which her husband had disappeared; <ambient_sound> when the roar of the storm and the distant sound of the sea ceased for a moment</ambient_sound>, she flinched as if in terror; she now felt as if everything were seeking only to destroy him, and would suddenly fall silent when it had seized him. Her knees trembled, the storm had loosened her hair and was playing with it.  " Here is the child, woman! " <character_sound> John shouted to her</character_sound>; " hold it tight! " and pressed the little one into her mother's arms.    " The child? - I had forgotten about you, Wienke! " <character_sound> she cried</character_sound>; " God forgive me. " Then she lifted it to her breast, as firmly as only love can hold it, and fell to her knees with it: " Lord God and You my Jesus, don't let us become widows or orphans! Protect him, O dear God; only you and I, we alone know him! " And the storm did not cease; <ambient_sound> it sounded and thundered</ambient_sound> as if the whole world were to perish in a tremendous reverberation and noise.    " Go into the house, woman! " <character_sound> said John</character_sound>; " come! " and he helped them up and led them into the house and into the parlour.  </scene>


  <scene counter="105">- - The dyke count Hauke Haien chased towards the dyke on his grey horse. The narrow path had no bottom, for immense rain had fallen the days before; but the wet, absorbent clay did not seem to hold the animal's hooves, it was as if it had solid summer ground beneath it. The clouds drifted in the sky like a wild chase; below, the wide marsh lay like an unrecognisable desert filled with restless shadows; from the water behind the dyke, <ambient_sound> ever more immense, came a dull roar</ambient_sound>, as if it must devour everything else.  " Forward, mould! " <character_sound> Hauke shouted</character_sound>; " we're riding our worst ride! " <ambient_sound> It sounded like a death cry under the hooves of his horse</ambient_sound>. He pulled back the reins; he looked round: to his side, close above the ground, half flying, half tossed by the storm, <ambient_sound> a flock of white gulls drew near, uttering a mocking cackle</ambient_sound>; they were seeking shelter in the land. One of them - the moon shone fleetingly through the clouds - lay trampled on the path: the rider felt as if a red ribbon were fluttering on her neck.   " Claus! " <character_sound> he cried</character_sound>.  " Poor Claus! " Was it his child's bird? Had he recognised the horse and rider and wanted to hide with them? - The rider didn't know.  " Onwards! " <character_sound> he called again</character_sound>, and already the grey horse lifted his hooves to run again, then the storm suddenly stopped, <ambient_sound> a deathly silence took its place</ambient_sound>; only for a second, then it came back with renewed fury; <ambient_sound>but human voices and the lost barking of dogs had meanwhile reached the rider's ear</ambient_sound>, and as he turned his head backwards towards his village, he recognised in the moonlight that was breaking out, people in the docks and in front of the houses, handling heavily laden carts; he saw, as if in flight, other carts hurrying up to the Geest; <ambient_sound> the bellowing of cattle met his ear</ambient_sound> as they were driven up there from the warm stables.  " Thank God! They are about to save themselves and their cattle! " it cried within him; <character_sound>and then with a cry of fear</character_sound>: " My wife! My child! - No, no; the water will not rise on our shipyard! " But it was only a moment; everything flashed past him like a vision. <ambient_sound> A terrible gust came roaring from the sea</ambient_sound>, and against it, horse and rider rushed up the narrow path to the dyke. When they reached the top, Hauke stopped his horse by force. But where was the sea? Where was Jeverssand? Where was the shore over there? - All he could see before him were mountains of water, towering against the night sky, trying to pile up on top of each other in the terrible twilight and beating against the solid land. <ambient_sound> With white crowns they came howling</ambient_sound>, as if they contained the cry of all the terrible predators of the wild nature. <ambient_sound> The grey horse beat its front hooves</ambient_sound> <ambient_sound> and snorted with its nostrils into the noise</ambient_sound>; but the rider was overcome as if all human power had come to an end here; as if night, death, nothingness must now fall.  But he recollected himself: it was storm tide; only he had never seen it like this himself; his wife, his child, they were safe on the high wharf, in the solid house; but his dyke - and it flew through his chest like pride - the Hauke-Haiendeich, as the people called him, he might now prove how dykes should be built!  But - what was that? - He stopped at the corner between the two dykes; where were the people he had put here to keep watch? - He looked northwards up the old dyke, for he had ordered some people there too. Neither here nor there was he able to see a human being; he rode out a little way, but he remained alone; <ambient_sound> only the blowing of the storm and the roar of the sea from an immeasurable distance beat deafeningly on his ear</ambient_sound>. He turned the horse back; he came again to the deserted corner and let his eyes glide along the line of the new dyke; he recognised clearly: slower, less violent were the waves rolling in here; it almost seemed as if there was another water there.  " It should stand already! " <character_sound> he murmured</character_sound>, and it rose in him like a laugh.  But the laughter faded as his eyes slid further along the line of his dyke: at the north-west corner - what was that there? A dark crowd was swarming around; he saw them bustling and pushing - no doubt about it, they were people! What did they want, what were they doing on his dyke now? - And already his spurs were in the grey horse's points, and the animal flew along with him; the storm came from the broadside; sometimes the gusts were so violent that they were almost hurled off the dyke into the new Koog; but horse and rider knew where they were riding. Hauke realised that a few dozen people were busily at work there, and he could already see clearly that a channel had been dug right through the new dyke. He stopped his horse violently: " Stop! " <character_sound> he shouted</character_sound>; " stop! What devil's nonsense are you doing here? " They had let their spades rest in fright when they suddenly recognised the dyke count among them; the storm had brought his words to them, and he could see that several of them were trying to answer him, but he only saw their violent gestures; for they all stood to his left, <ambient_sound>and what they spoke</ambient_sound> was taken away by the storm, which out here now sometimes tossed people against each other as if in a frenzy, so that they clustered close together. With his quick eyes, Hauke measured the dug channel and the level of the water, which, despite the new profile, almost reached the height of the dyke and splashed over horse and rider. Just ten more minutes of work - he could see it coming - then the high tide would break through the channel and the Hauke-Haienkoog would be buried by the sea!  The dyke count beckoned one of the labourers to the other side of his horse.  " Now, speak up! " <character_sound> he shouted</character_sound>, " what are you doing here, what do you mean? " <ambient_sound> And the human shouted against it</ambient_sound>: " We should pierce the new dyke, Lord! so that the old dyke doesn't break! " " What shall you do? " - " Pierce the new dyke! " " And bury the Koog? - What devil told you to do that? " " No, sir, not a devil; the plenipotentiary Ole Peters was here; <character_sound> he ordered it</character_sound>! " Anger rose in the rider's eyes: "Do you know me? " <character_sound> he shouted</character_sound>.  " Where I am, Ole Peters has nothing to ordain! Away with you! To your places, where I have put you! " And as they hesitated, he dashed between them with his grey horse: " Away, to your or the devil's grandmother! " " Lord, beware! " <ambient_sound> cried one of the crowd</ambient_sound> and struck with his spade at the furiously behaving animal; but a hoof-beat flung the spade from his hand, and another fell to the ground. <ambient_sound> Suddenly a cry arose from the rest of the crowd</ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound> a cry such as only the fear of death can wrench from a human throat</ambient_sound>; for a moment everything, including the dyke count and the grey horse, was paralysed; only one worker had stretched out his arm like a signpost, pointing to the north-west corner of the two dykes, where the new one met the old one. <ambient_sound> Only the roar of the storm and the sound of the water could be heard</ambient_sound>. Hauke turned in the saddle: what was that? His eyes grew wide: " Lord God! A breach! A breach in the old dyke! " " Your fault, dyke count! " <ambient_sound> a voice shouted from the crowd</ambient_sound>: " Your fault! Take it to God's throne! " Hauke's angry red face had turned deathly pale; the moon that shone on it could not make it paler; his arms hung limp, he hardly knew that he was holding the reins.  </scene>


  <scene counter="107"> But even that was only a moment; already he straightened up,<character_sound> a harsh groan broke from his mouth</character_sound>;<character_sound> then he silently turned his horse</character_sound>, <ambient_sound> and the grey horse snorted</ambient_sound> and raced eastwards along the dyke with him. The rider's eyes flew sharply in all directions; in his head the thoughts raged: What guilt did he have to bear before God's throne? - The breaching of the new dyke - perhaps, they would have done it, if he had not called his halt; but - it was one more thing, and it shot hot to his heart, he knew it only too well - last summer, if Ole Peters' wicked mouth had not held him back then - there it was! He alone had recognised the weakness of the old dyke; despite everything, he should have gone ahead with the new work: " Lord God, yes, I confess it, " <character_sound>he suddenly cried out loudly into the storm</character_sound>, " I have done a poor job! " To his left, close to the horse's hoofs,<ambient_sound> the sea raged</ambient_sound>; before him, and now in full darkness, lay the old Koog with its dockyards and homely houses; the pale light of the sky was completely extinguished; only from one spot did a glimmer of light break through the darkness. And it came like a comfort to the man's heart; it must have shone from his house, it was like a greeting from his wife and child. Thank God, they were safe on the high wharf! The others, of course, were already in the Geestdorf above; from there shone a light such as he had never seen before; even from high up in the air, it might have been from the church tower, such light broke out into the night.  " They'll all be gone, all of them! " <character_sound> Hauke said to himself</character_sound>; " of course, on many a shipyard a house will lie in ruins, bad years will come for the flooded fens; sluices and locks will have to be repaired! We must bear it, and I will help, even those who have done me harm; only, Lord my God, have mercy on us men! " Then he cast his eyes sideways towards the new bog; the sea foamed around him, but within him lay a nightly peace. <character_sound> An involuntary shout burst from the rider's chest</character_sound>: "The Hauke-Haiendeich, it shall hold; it will still do so after a hundred years! " </scene>


  <scene counter="108"><ambient_sound>A thunderous roar at his feet woke him from these dreams</ambient_sound>; the grey horse no longer wanted to move forward. What was that? - The horse jumped back and he felt it, a piece of dyke plunged into the depths in front of him. He opened his eyes and shook all his senses: he stopped at the old dyke, the grey horse had already stood on it with its front hooves. Involuntarily he pulled the horse back; then the last clouds flew from the moon, and the mild star illuminated the grey, which plunged foaming, hissing into the depths before him, down into the old Koog.  Hauke stared at it senselessly; it was a flood to devour animals and men. Then the light flashed into his eyes again; it was the same light that he had seen earlier; it was still burning on his shipyard; and as he now looked down into the bog with renewed vigour, he saw that behind the confusing whirlpool <ambient_sound>thundering down in front of him</ambient_sound>, only a width of about a hundred paces was still flooded; behind it he could clearly see the path leading from the bog. He saw even more: a carriage, no, a two-wheeled carriole was approaching the dyke like a madman; a woman and even a child were sitting in it. And now - <ambient_sound> wasn't that the screeching barking of a small dog</ambient_sound> flying past in the storm? God almighty! It was his wife, his child; they were already coming close, and the foaming mass of water was rushing towards them. <character_sound> A cry, a cry of despair burst from the rider's chest</character_sound>: " Elke! " <character_sound> he shouted</character_sound>; " Elke! Get back! Get back! " But the storm and the sea were not merciful, <ambient_sound>their rage blew away his words</ambient_sound>; only his coat had been seized by the storm, it would soon have torn him from his horse; and the carriage flew towards the falling tide without stopping. Then he saw the woman stretching out her arms as if towards him: had she recognised him? Had her longing, her mortal fear for him, driven her from the safety of her house? And now - was she calling out one last word to him? - The questions raced through his brain; they remained unanswered: from her to him, from him to her, the words were all lost; <ambient_sound> only a roar as of the end of the world filled her ears</ambient_sound> and let no other sound in.    " My child! O Elke, o faithful Elke! " <character_sound> Hauke cried out into the storm</character_sound>. Then a large part of the dyke sank into the depths before him anew, <ambient_sound>and the sea thundered behind it</ambient_sound>; once more he saw the horse's head below, the wheels of the vehicle emerge from the desolate abomination and then sink whirling into it. The staring eyes of the rider, who stood so lonely on the dyke, saw nothing else.  " The end! " <character_sound> he said quietly to himself</character_sound>; then he rode to the abyss, <ambient_sound> where below him the waters, rushing eerily, began to flood his home village</ambient_sound>; he still saw the light shimmering from his house; it was as if he were unseen. He reared himself up and thrust his spurs into the grey horse's soft points; the animal reared up, it almost rolled over, but the man's strength pushed it down.  " Forward! " <character_sound> he shouted once more</character_sound>, as he had shouted so often for a firm ride: " Lord God, take me; spare the others! " Another spur thrust; <ambient_sound> a cry of the grey horse</ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound> which overcame storm and roaring waves</ambient_sound>; <ambient_sound> then below from the plunging stream a muffled sound</ambient_sound>, a brief struggle.  The moon shone brightly from above; but down on the dyke there was no more life, only the wild waters, which had soon almost completely flooded the old Koog. But the shipyard of Hauke Haien's Hofstatt still protruded from the surge, the light still shimmered from there, and from the Geest, where the houses were gradually becoming dark, the lonely lamp from the church tower still threw its trembling sparks of light over the foaming waves. " </scene>


  <scene counter="109"><character_sound>The narrator was silent</character_sound>; I reached for the full glass that had been standing in front of me for a long time; but I did not bring it to my mouth; my hand remained resting on the table.    "That is the story of Hauke Haien," <character_sound> began my host once more</character_sound>, " <character_sound> as I could only tell it to the best of my knowledge</character_sound>. Of course, the landlady of our dyke count would have told it to you differently; for this is also known to be reported: that white horse carcass was seen again after the flood, as before, in the moonlight on Jevershallig; the whole village claims to have seen it. - This much is certain: Hauke Haien and his wife and child perished in this flood; I have not even been able to find their burial place up in the churchyard; the dead bodies will have been driven out to sea by the outflowing water through the breach and gradually disintegrated into their original parts at the bottom of the sea - so they were at peace from human beings. But the Hauke-Haiendeich still stands after a hundred years, and if you ride to the city tomorrow and don't want to shy away from the half-hour diversions, you'll have it under your horse's hooves. <character_sound>The thanks which Jeve Manners once promised his builder among his grandchildren</character_sound> have, as you have seen, failed to materialise; for so it is, sir: they gave Socrates a poison to drink and our Lord Christ they nailed to the cross! That is no longer so easy in the last times; but - to make a violent man or a wicked bull-necked clergyman a saint, or an able-bodied fellow, just because he outgrew us by the length of his head, into a ghost and a spectre of the night - that is still possible every day. " <character_sound> When the serious little man had said this</character_sound>, he stood up and listened outside.  "Something has changed there," <character_sound> he said</character_sound> and pulled the woollen blanket from the window; it was bright moonlight.   " Look, " <character_sound> he continued</character_sound>, " there the plenipotentiaries are coming back; but they are dispersing, they are going home; - over on the other bank a breach must have happened; the water has fallen. " I looked out beside him; the windows up here were over the edge of the dyke; it was, <character_sound>as he had said</character_sound>. I took my glass and drank the rest: " Thank you for this evening! " <character_sound> I said</character_sound>; " I think we can sleep peacefully! " " We can; " <character_sound> replied the little gentleman</character_sound>; " <character_sound> I sincerely wish you a good night's sleep</character_sound>! " </scene>


  <scene counter="110">- - As I was going downstairs, I met the dike count in the corridor; he wanted to take home a card he had left in the tavern.  " All over! " <character_sound> he said</character_sound>.  " But our schoolmaster must have taught you a thing or two; he's one of the enlightened ones! " - " He seems an intelligent man! " " Yes, yes, certainly; but you can't trust your own eyes; and over on the other side, <character_sound>I predicted it</character_sound>, the dyke has broken! " I shrugged my shoulders: " That has to be slept on! Good night, Mr Dike Count! " <character_sound> He laughed</character_sound>: " Good night! " - - The next morning, in the most golden sunlight that had risen over a vast desolation, I rode down the Hauke-Haien dyke to the town.  </scene>
         </body>
     </text>
</TEI>