<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title>Viebig_Clara_The_Cigar_Worker_anno.csv.xml</title>
        </titleStmt>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <title>The cigar worker</title>
Every day, twelve o'clock on the dot, they came down the mountain. their seven, eight. Maria Josefa Brand led the way. Her blue printed dress blew in the wind, the tousled brown strands fluttering at the nape of her neck, her slightly reddened eyelids squinting in the light. A penetrating smell of tobacco wafted in front of the girls like an acrid vapour from their hair and skirts. They all had the same reddened, squinting eyelids, and when they spoke their voices sounded muffled - cigar workers. From seven in the morning until midday, and then again from early afternoon until the dark evening, they squatted in the low rooms of the tobacco factory in Ober-Manderscheid. They bent their young bodies over the shelves of dried leaves, their fingers rustling busily in them, the acrid odour filling their eyes with tears, a tickling cough tormenting their throats. The window panes froze in the thick air. Maria Josefa Brand was the best worker, the nimblest. She didn't look up, no wave of blood coloured her pale face, she didn't speak. The only thing whirring through her mind was: "Thirty pfennigs a hundred, thirty pfennigs! " She pressed her lips together when the others laughed. And yet she was young. Her slender limbs twitched with life, her blood boiled at times and throbbed with desire. On anxious nights she tossed restlessly on the straw sack, and when she heard a pair of lovers whispering in the bush, she felt hot and cold. But she never looked at a boy. She never let anyone give her a colourful ribbon or a sugar heart at a funfair. she never went to the dance. Down in Nieder-Manderscheid, in the dark hut clinging to the mighty castle ruins like a swallow's nest, she sat with her old grandfather. She spent the whole summer Sunday mucking about and clogging up. She didn't like to go ragged, and during the week the factory took up all her time. When the shadows stretched long and deep down the mountain walls, she rubbed her tired eyes - they always hurt from the acrid tobacco fumes - yawned and stretched her brownish arms above her head. " Where are you going? " <character_sound> asked the old grandfather</character_sound>. He was always suspicious, he didn't trust anyone. He could no longer see well, let alone hear, he lived in a time twenty years ago. In winter and summer he crouched by the cooker, snow-white stubble around his weathered mouth, a childish look in his pale blue eyes. He didn't like to go out into the light, he was only comfortable inside in the dull air. <character_sound> he growled unwillingly</character_sound>, a cheeky ray of sunlight danced through the crack in the door and coated his dirty hands in gold. " Where are you, Lena? " <character_sound> asked his toothless mouth</character_sound> when his granddaughter stretched on Sunday. " Gieh net danzen - Jesses! " And then he ran both hands through his shaggy hair and rocked his head back and forth: " Holy Mary, Moddergotts, pray for us, now on the hour of our death! Have mercy on her! " " Grandfather " -<character_sound> Maria Josefa shouted loudly in his ears </character_sound> - " I'm not a Lena! E ne, ech giehn net danzen! " The old man grinned with satisfaction <character_sound> and tapped her on the head </character_sound> : " E su es et recht, Lena - jao, jao! " Impatiently she shook off his hand , then she threw open her lips with a contemptuous twitch - ba, dance! She didn't go dancing, she wasn't like her mother, Lena, who had to jump after every fiddle. What had been the end of the song? Someone had abandoned her, with a child to boot. Her father had beaten her and people had laughed at her - you wouldn't believe how cruel people are! Lena hadn't grown old, she'd been lying in the churchyard for a long time. her child had grown up with her grandfather - - - - " Maria Josefa, who's dad?! " Maria Josefa already knew the whole story when she was not yet ten years old. there was a precocious expression around the child's mouth, the corners of her mouth were pulled down: Don't go dancing, don't look at boys, that was the right thing to do! - Maria Josefa pushed the cottage door open with her foot <ambient_sound> and let it fall creaking into the lock behind her </ambient_sound> . <ambient_sound> the nail-studded shoes pattered over the rubble </ambient_sound> . She didn't have far to go, the back wall of the hut leaned against the defiantly towering watchtower. Now she was in the middle of the ruins. It was already dusk in the old walls. <ambient_sound> Startled birds came cawing out of the tower </ambient_sound> , <ambient_sound> rustling and trickling in the corners </ambient_sound> . <ambient_sound> quietly it crept </ambient_sound> and pressed itself against her feet. With a laugh, she bent down and lifted a grey cat, still a young, barely grown animal, into her arms. The joy coloured her cheeks red. " Kitty, kitty! "<ambient_sound> The grey one purred </ambient_sound> and cuddled, bumping its head against the girl's chest. " O dau " - Maria Josefa pressed the animal to her, she clenched her teeth with tenderness,<character_sound> so that they gnashed</character_sound> - " wuh warste e su lang? Oh dau - kitty, kitty! " <ambient_sound> The cat replied, meowing softly</ambient_sound> . She blinked at her mistress out of slanted green eyes, then kicked and leapt out of the holding arms in one bound. Tail raised high, head turned back again and again to see if she was being followed, she hurried towards the darkest corner. What did she have there? Maria Josefa approached curiously -<ambient_sound> the grey one meowed</ambient_sound> , <ambient_sound> a thin squeak, like a mouse whistle answered </ambient_sound> - the girl backed away. Seven little blind cats were lying there on a ball of dry leaves and brushwood, as if in a nest. The grey one stood over them with her legs spread, <ambient_sound> cooed like a dove </ambient_sound>, turned the unhelpful things back and forth and licked them tenderly.<ambient_sound> Squealing, the kittens pressed themselves against their mother's shivering body </ambient_sound> . " Ba! " Maria Josefa twisted her mouth and spat out. " Ba, dau disgusting Dier! " There was no longer a trace of joy in her face. She stared angrily at the young brood, her brows drawn together. As the grey one wiggled and stroked her dress ingratiatingly, she raised her foot to push: " Dau sollst net - ech will net! " <character_sound> A squeezed breath lifted her chest </character_sound> . narrowing her eyes, she turned away. <ambient_sound> The stones clattered under her footsteps </ambient_sound> , a shred of her blue skirt caught on the brambles, the thorny vines hit her calves. Now she swung herself into the hollow window parapet of the old tower and gazed thoughtlessly into the distance. The few houses of Nieder-Manderscheid were already grey in the grey, swallowed up by the darkness in the gorge. The mountain slopes were gloomy, their short green playing into blackness, only beyond, on the very top, Ober-Manderscheid with the pointed slate church tower, bathed in evening light. <ambient_sound> From there came singing </ambient_sound> .<ambient_sound> that blew down </ambient_sound> <ambient_sound> and broke deeper on the blackish shadows </ambient_sound> . Those were the young boys and girls! On Sundays they liked to walk along the edge of the mountain, cheering and throwing stones down the gorge into the foaming Lieser.  <ambient_sound> Now they were singing a love song </ambient_sound> . <ambient_sound> The long, drawn-out notes echoed </ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound>they did not die away</ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound>new ones always followed</ambient_sound>. The lonely woman flinched and pressed her hands to her ears. She crouched on the perilous seat for a long time, her feet dangling down, <character_sound>her heels knocking incessantly on the rotten stones</character_sound>. Below her the abyss. When she took her hands off her ears, <ambient_sound> no more love song sounded </ambient_sound> . <ambient_sound>only the Lieser rushed</ambient_sound> <ambient_sound>and murmured</ambient_sound> <ambient_sound>and the bats buzzed</ambient_sound>. It was night. Maria Josefa was not afraid. This was how her Sunday amusement always was. <character_sound>Slowly she slithered home to her grandfather</character_sound>. Now she stumbled over the stones, she had thrown her head back and sucked in the damp night air with flared nostrils. " Laoß se sing, " <character_sound> she muttered defiantly </character_sound> - " laoß se! Thirty pfennigs dat Hunnert, thirty pfennigs - ech verdeenen money, ech haon niemand nedig - ech will ken Schatz - ech sein net wie et Lena! " <character_sound> She laughed briefly</character_sound>. <ambient_sound> the walls echoed again</ambient_sound>. Now she flinched. Something scurried past her - the cat! <character_sound> With an expletive, she grabbed a stone </character_sound> and hurled it into the darkness.

Up in Manderscheid, in the new white house that shone brightly in the sunshine, lived a man who was different from all the others in the village. He was fine, a city gentleman who had travelled from far away. He wasn't English either. He roamed the woods and hunted, or he sat around and painted. He spent half days in the castle ruins, <character_sound> even the old grandfather shuffled into the cottage door</character_sound> and stared over. Maria Josefa knew the stranger, too - he had a face like the knight George who stabs the lindworm to death, and eyes that looked you through and through. she had to cast down her inflamed eyelids when he met her. It was like being bewitched. <ambient_sound> Always at noon</ambient_sound>, when they jumped down the mountain, her seven, eight - Maria Josefa first - then he came up. <character_sound>He bid them good day</character_sound>, the girls greeted him again bashfully. <character_sound> One of them, the plump Trina, giggled and hid her simple-minded, pudgy child's face behind Maria Josefa's back </character_sound>. Only she didn't say hello. An invisible hand pressed down on her neck, and yet it wanted to pull her head up again. she didn't realise how funny it was. He looked at her in particular, she felt it. As if whipped, she chased ahead, <ambient_sound> so that the scree pattered behind her </ambient_sound> . At the bottom of the mountain she had to stop, her breath had run out. She looked around timidly - he was still standing there. And one day he came into the factory, his tall figure barely able to get through the low door. He looked around everywhere, the supervisor led him through every room. " Very interesting to me, very interesting indeed, " <character_sound> he said to him </character_sound>, stepping up to each table, touching the cigars, examining them carefully <character_sound>and then putting them down again</character_sound> with a laugh. " It's really worthy of all honour that you've managed to do this here in this remote village, it brings merit to the people. How much is there for the hundred? " He stood close to Maria Josefa and looked down at her. Her fingers were trembling, the wrapper was tearing, the tobacco was spilling out and the wrapper was unusable. She rudely threw it to fat Trina, who opened her eyes in astonishment - this had hardly ever happened to Maria Josefa! " Been clumsy?! " <character_sound> The stranger didn't say it at all mockingly</character_sound>, and yet the tone made the girl's cheeks flush. what did he have to ask? Blindly she reached for a new wrap. it flickered before her eyes,<character_sound> the gentleman's hand with the shiny nails and the flashing ring, rummaged in the rustling brown leaves </character_sound> and let it slide playfully through her fingers. What a beautiful hand it was, not so knotty around the joints, well tanned, but not like leather and soft at that! Did he have a girl who had given him that sparkling ring? What must she have looked like to please him - - -? She flinched. "Well, how much will you get for the hundred? How much will you get for the hundred, child?" <character_sound> He spoke to Trina</character_sound>, who didn't know how to answer, she was so stupid! Shame came over Maria Josefa. what must he think of them all? A glowing wave of blood shot into her face up to the brown ripples at her temples - even if she ruffled it with water and pulled it back, it always rippled anew - <character_sound> she cleared her throat</character_sound> , the tobacco dust tickled her throat, <character_sound> and then she said loudly</character_sound> : " Thirty pfennigs for a hundred, sir! " She struggled to speak High German. " Only?! " The hand with the flashing ring stopped rummaging in the dry leaves. " And how many hundred do you manage a day? " " Four hundred, five hundred, depending. I earn as much as one mark twenty a day - I also earn the most! " <character_sound> She said it proudly</character_sound>, suddenly feeling like the best, the smartest worker. " Poor thing! " His hand placed itself on her shoulder. heavy, warm, squeezing that one. She felt it through the thin blue print dress, it trickled down her arm and down her back. It ran hot and cold through her veins. She couldn't have lifted her head, not for anything in the world. She lowered it lower and lower. Her fingers clumsily gripped the leaves. " That's little - one mark twenty - dear God! " <character_sound> His voice sounded regretful</character_sound> . " Why don't you go into service? You have it better there! " The girls sitting around bumped into each other <ambient_sound> and giggled </ambient_sound> - so stupid, so simple-minded - they didn't even understand <character_sound>what the gentleman was actually saying</character_sound> ! Maria Josefa understood him, she understood that he pitied her, and she wanted no pity, least of all from him. She made a violent movement, so that the burdening hand slipped from her shoulder. Defiantly she looked up from below, the dark eyes under the half-lowered inflamed lids still had an unclouded lustre. "I'm not poor, I don't need pity, I don't need anyone! In service? No! " Her lips twisted disdainfully and she gave him a quick glance from the side, which he caught and held. Her eyelids blinked - what was the use, she had to endure, she had to look at him fully, while her fingers mechanically turned the cigar and her knees trembled as if she had been walking downhill over steep scree for hours. "So " - the stranger now slowly turned away - " and I thought you might come to work for me. I'm looking for a young girl to help the old woman in my house. So you don't want to? Well, don't be too busy - goodbye! " <character_sound> He nodded to her</character_sound>, all alone, it seemed to her. <character_sound> He had also called her " you " </character_sound> , Kruft's Trina only " you " - and he had wanted to take her into service, why her - her of all people - - -? " No, no! " Maria Josefa's cheeks flamed, she jumped up and banged the table so hard that a handful of cigars rolled down. The others turned their heads towards her in astonishment for a moment, then bent over the work again.<ambient_sound> Nothing could be heard but the rustling of the dry herbs </ambient_sound> and now and then <ambient_sound> a dry cough </ambient_sound> . Brownish dust flew around, with every movement the smell of tobacco fluttered from the girls' clothes and hair. an acrid vapour rose to the whitewashed ceiling and crept heavily along the walls. Today, Kruft's Trina had more daily wages than Maria Josefa. She didn't jump down the hill ahead of the others either, she strolled along behind, disgruntled. Tomorrow was Sunday. <ambient_sound> She heard the girls telling each other </ambient_sound> . Each had her treasure, even fat Trina with the pudgy, simple-minded child's face had one. " Hän gieht met mer danzen morjen, " <character_sound> said Trina </character_sound> and opened her mouth wide - " ze Bleckfeld es Kirmes, mer maachen daorhin. Ju! " <character_sound> She laughed </character_sound> <ambient_sound> and the others laughed too </ambient_sound> . <ambient_sound> As if in a dream, Maria Josefa heard the chatter </ambient_sound> . <ambient_sound> Behind her, the evening bell rang from the pointed slate church </ambient_sound> , <ambient_sound> there was something of joy in every bell sound </ambient_sound> . <ambient_sound>the sound floated softly over the roofs of Ober-Manderscheid</ambient_sound> and over the churchyard with the white crosses on the edge of the hill. <character_sound> Maria Josefa stood still</character_sound> and looked back, suddenly thinking of her mother - she was lying there. The houses of Nieder-Manderscheid had disappeared, completely engulfed in scent. The slopes of the gorge no longer greenish-black in colour, long white mists rising up and down them. <ambient_sound>The Lieser rushes wild and white-foaming, swollen by plunging pours</ambient_sound>. <ambient_sound>In the steaming forests, the deer cry out</ambient_sound>. <ambient_sound>At night, the rutting cry reaches the huts</ambient_sound>, <ambient_sound>refracts on the rock faces</ambient_sound> <ambient_sound>and fades into a hollow echo</ambient_sound>. Maria Josefa sat awake on her straw sack and covered her ears. <ambient_sound> she heard every scream</ambient_sound>, and then she flinched. Was she afraid? Over by the wall lay her old grandfather <character_sound> and snored</character_sound>. <character_sound>he sometimes rattled so</character_sound> that she got up, lit a light and went to him. He looked like a dead man, his eyes sunken, his mouth open. but he was warm, he was just sleeping. She stood in front of him for a long time. The light cast her lonely shadow on the wall, flickering ghostly across the weathered old man's face. The hot tallow dripped down onto her bare feet. With wide, unthinking eyes, without feeling, she stared straight ahead, and then suddenly she shuddered and shook herself. <character_sound> She blew out the light </character_sound> and jumped back onto her straw bag in one leap. She curled up to warm herself, feeling the softness of her own limbs, <character_sound>her heart began to pound, wild and impetuous</character_sound>. <character_sound>it beat hard against her ribs</character_sound>. All sorts of images flashed past her narrowed eyes - - - how Kruft's Trina hung from her sweetheart's neck in love! - - how the supervisor's wife in the factory had her little one on her breast! - - oh, how blissful they were! - - Sweat beaded on her forehead. "Thirty pfennigs a hundred, thirty pfennigs - nobody needs it" - that had been like a magic spell. She used to say it to herself and become calm and proud, but not anymore. " Poor thing, " <character_sound>he had said</character_sound>, despite the thirty pfennigs! " Jesus Maria! " She folded her hands. She had never prayed as much as she had in the last few months. she was afraid and yet it made her laugh. one day she was contrite, the next she lifted her head haughtily above her companions. Which of them could boast that a fine gentleman with a face like St George's and a hand with a glittering ring on it was following her? With this hand he had gently stroked her cheeks and chin, the other day in the ruins - and yesterday -?! " Jeez! " She flapped her arms as if searching for something - nothing! Everything empty, everything dark - but no, stop! It crawled out from behind the cooker, <ambient_sound> mewled pitifully</ambient_sound> and snuggled up to her trembling body. It was the grey one! She was all alone now too, all her young dead! Maria Josefa had thrown them into the stream with her own hand, the little bodies had been swept away in a whirl. she had stared after them impassively. <ambient_sound> But when the grey one, wailing piteously</ambient_sound>, walked around her desolate nest, searching every corner with ruffled fur and curled tail, tears had welled up in Maria Josefa's eyes. <character_sound>With a muffled sound, she had embraced the cat</character_sound>. They had been inseparable ever since. weren't they both alone? Maria Josefa now pressed the animal to her with passionate tenderness, her hands cramped into the fur and tugged at it. Then she lifted the cat up into the air, as one lifts a child in an excess of love. The cat's eyes sparkled above her in a greenish light, two fiery dots in the darkness. " Huh, haste mech lief, gel dau, gel -? " <ambient_sound> The grey growled</ambient_sound>, the position was uncomfortable for her. she didn't scratch, but she wrapped her sharp claws around the holding hand. Sobered, the girl lowered her bare arms - huh, cold! Autumn! Winter was coming soon. And the hut so miserable, and the nights so long, and always, always alone! She had never thought about it before. The factory and coffee and potatoes and heat and cold, that was enough to think about - but now -? Shivering, she pulled the ragged blanket up to her chin. the cat lay on her chest. Now she was warm, but she couldn't sleep, <ambient_sound> the deer cried muffled in the nearby forest</ambient_sound> - through the darkness two eyes bored into hers, eyes that see you through and through - and a hand moved back and forth in front of her, came closer and closer, stroked her cheeks and chin so close that she felt the breeze, reached out for her shoulder, for her chest - - " Ha! " <character_sound> With a muffled scream of fear, Maria Josefa went up</character_sound> so that the cat rolled off her chest. With a wild gesture she threw her arms over her head, <character_sound>sobbing</character_sound>: "No, no - I don't like it - but no - and no! " - - How the day slowly creeps up, how it then drags on! Maria Josefa dragged her limbs heavily, her eyelids were more inflamed than usual. She had worked furiously in the factory, the cigars flying under her hands. <ambient_sound> At noon she had climbed down the hill</ambient_sound>, far, far behind the others - there he was. <character_sound>He said "Good afternoon"</character_sound> <character_sound>and laughed at her</character_sound>. <character_sound>She had laughed again</character_sound> <character_sound>and had to say " Good day "</character_sound>, he was so handsome, too fine a gentleman - and how the ring on his hand flashed! The only ray of the pale autumn sun sparkled on it. <character_sound>He had been talking to her for a long time</character_sound>. And now it was evening. Outside, everything was a deep grey. <ambient_sound>The Lieser roared stormily</ambient_sound> and overflowed its banks. <ambient_sound>In the forest, the deer cry out</ambient_sound> - hunting time. Maria Josefa crouches in the narrowest corner of the hut, huddled like a woman burdened with guilt. She is indistinctly visible, no light is burning, only the brushwood fire on the hearth is glowing. She clutches the cat with both arms. Now she bends even lower and lays her head on the soft fur. <character_sound>She breathes hastily</character_sound> - - - What did he say? " Maria Josefa, come out - tonight, behind the ruins, in the forest by the big fir tree - Maria Josefa, you must come - come, Maria Josefa, come! " - - - " Where are you going? " <character_sound>asks the old grandfather behind the stove</character_sound> and blinks his stupid eyes. <character_sound>She gives no answer</character_sound>. She gets up with difficulty, walks to the door with shaking legs. " Where were you -? " The door slams shut. Maria Josefa stands outside in the dark. The world is shrouded in mist. The night dew falls like tears on her hair, her clothes become damp. - - Come, Maria Josefa, come - come - - -! With her hot mouth thirstily open, with beating, feverish pulses, Maria Josefa walks through the night, slowly at first, then quickly. <ambient_sound>There the Lieser roars</ambient_sound>, there the ruins loom like blackish lumps - now, <ambient_sound>now the first forest trees are rustling</ambient_sound>! She walks faster and faster, she stumbles, she pulls herself together, she runs, <character_sound>her feet rustle in the dry leaves</character_sound>.  <character_sound>her breath flies</character_sound>, <character_sound>she is frightened by her own panting</character_sound>. Beneath the flimsy dress, her chest trembles and quivers, her forehead glows. there is no sense, no thought, only a throbbing, a chasing and an urging. Moonlight glides over the path, a bird flies up - she runs and runs. There is the fir tree, a shadow on its trunk, a figure! It rushes forward, arms outstretched in front of it, head thrown back - - - - And yet! When spring came, Maria Josefa danced at every fair, every Sunday. She danced wildly, with her hair flowing, her skirts fluttering and her eyes sparkling. When she was tired, she went to her mother's grave in the churchyard. There she sat. The grave was sunken, with weeds and grass growing on it. A dishevelled wreath hung from the rotten wooden cross.
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
